Jeremy E. Muniak - Junior Full Stack Developer/ Senior Recruitment Consultant

Portland, Maine 04101 [p] 774.232.9180 [e] jeremy.e.muniak@gmail.com LinkedIn

My goal is to make a meaningful impact at a dynamic business with upstanding values through my skills and education with Full Stack Development techniques and technologies.

Summary:

Starting my career in Life and Health Insurance Sales was a truly great experience despite being a 1099 commission only environment. It cut my teeth in a competitive industry and propelled my abilities in closing, customer service, and communication. It taught me a wealth of hard and soft skills I'll use through life and in every job.

As a seasoned Full Cycle Recruiter, I have enjoyed helping I.T., Telecom, and a variety of other Executive Professionals grow their careers by leading them into new opportunities.

Now I'm pursuing a career as a full stack developer after learning the joys of development. Solving problems, making lives easier, constantly learning, and the gratification of making an app come to life have motivated my passion for development.

Skills: Software Training (+3 years), Leadership / Management (4-5 years), Administrative Organization, MS Office Suite, Certified SME in Outlook 2013, problem-solving troubleshooting, analyzing information, professionalism, excellent written or verbal communication.

Recruiting: Agency Recruiting (+2years), Corporate Talent Acquisition (1.5 years), BullHorn CRM/ATS (+2 years), Lever ATS (6 months).

Sales: B2B Sales (+3 years) B2C Sales (+10 years), SalesForce (1 year), GoToMeeting (3 years), Client / Customer Relationship Management / Negotiations (+6 years), Prospecting / Hunting New Business (+5 years).

IT: IT Helpdesk Support (+2 years), GoToMeeting (+3 years), Remote Desktop Connection (4 years), Beginner skills in VS Code, Git, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node.js, Bootstrap, Materialize, Firebase, and Visual Basic.

Professional Experience:

Certify, Inc. – Portland, ME. January 2018 – July 2019 Talent Acquisition Partner

Named one of the Best Places to Work in 2015, 2016, 2017 & 2018 Certify is disrupting the world of expense management with a simple and innovative cloud-based solution that's scalable for companies of every size and industry.

- As a Talent Acquisition Partner in Portland, ME HQ, my primary role is to drive employer branding
 and the entire candidate pipeline, for all open job requisitions, across 3 brands and international
 offices located throughout the US, Canada and in the UK. All while demonstrating the highest level of
 customer service and courtesy for each candidate in the process. Reported directly to the Chief
 People Officer of the combined brands.
- Directly responsible for implementing a new ATS software system, Lever, and creating all templates and SOPs to increase the efficiency of the candidate flow, from the application stage through the interview process. By using my skills combined with my leadership's support I created new best practices that have been successful in elevating the candidate experience and employer brand in meaningful ways. Large emphasis on Employer Branding initiatives such as networking events, career fairs, recipient of a Propel Initiate Award, involvement with local university alumni such as sponsoring Women in Leadership, and the Portland Chamber of Commerce, and a number of other career development opportunities.
- Organize and maintain a candidate pipeline for multiple managers across all departments. Personally handle 10-15 jobs at a time of various skill sets and levels, with complete autonomy. Achieved 10 new hires within one month as a one-man department in a variety of positions throughout various departments, locations, and levels of the organization.

- Duties also include creating all offers for new hires, both written and verbal, participating in and organizing participation in networking events, assisting with onboarding paperwork and background check authorization and processing.
- My accomplishments while in this role were numerous, I single-handedly filled more positions in the
 company than anyone in its history and was a key partner in the launch of Certify's U.K. location in
 London. The GlassDoor rating for the overall company and interview process sored while driving
 new employer branding techniques and the launch of a new ATS system while overhauling or
 creating every departmental screening template, and managing the talent pipeline for all positions
 within the multi-brand international organization.

Kelly Services - Contracted to Certify for a Temp Position - Portland, ME. January 2018 - May 2018 Recruiter

- As a Recruiter at Certify, Inc. my primary role is to source and screen applicants against a variety of open job requisitions while demonstrating the highest level of professionalism.
- Immediately after orientation and training, my impact was beyond the anticipated efficiency my management had expected. My full cycle agency recruiting experience enabled my ability to perform as a full cycle corporate recruiter handling 10-15 jobs at a time of various skill sets and levels, from Customer Support up to Sales Directors with complete autonomy.
- Due to my performance and dedication, I was converted to a full-time employee of Certify, Inc. in May of 2018.

Mountain, LTD. - New Gloucester, ME. September 2015 - December 2017 (2 years, 4 months) Telecommunications Recruiter / IT Administrator

- Full cycle agency recruitment within the Telecom Engineering and IT industry sectors specifically
 with a variety of positions under those umbrellas in several varied geographic locations that would
 often add additional challenges.
- Exceeded expected Revenue goal of \$575,000 by more than \$550,000 in the first year, over double the goal. This demonstrated an invaluable ability to learn quickly and hit the ground running while juggling additional responsibilities on the side such as training new hires and the IT Administrator duties shown below.
- Consistently placed 40+ calls a day while taking time to diligently research the job requisition details to find the best possible talent for major telecommunications providers like Verizon, CenturyLink, AT&T, Frontier, Spectrum, Windstream, and more. Occasional use VMS portals to submit applicants. Multitasked efficiently, managing time and prioritizing job orders properly. Gathered all required information to submit candidates under strict SOPs. Utilized Boolean search techniques to source the highest quality network engineers and IT professionals.
- IT Administrator duties in addition to regular Recruiting duties for Mountain over a year and a half, until they had the approval to hire a full-timer for these duties. Upon hire, I was immediately recognized as the "go-to person" for a resolution to technical issues around the office. IT duties, as needed, ranged from; setting up new computers/workstations, responding to general support requests, utilizing a remote desktop connection to access workstations nationwide as needed, accessing the active directory, etc. all in addition to the day to day recruiting activities and goals.
- Use of RJ-15 and RJ-45 test kits within the Switch Room to determine if certain ports were firing up with POE (Power Over Ethernet). As the Outlook 2013 SME for Mountain, LTD. I trained new employees on the use of Outlook 2013 with a self-made PowerPoint.

InterSpec, Inc. – South Portland, ME. May 2015 – September 2015 (5 months) Sales Engineer

- Hunted independently in a 100% new business B2B SaaS environment.
- Generated my own leads, drove those leads through the full cycle to close new business accounts. All through B2B prospecting to sell the SaaS solution of an Architectural Software Developer called InterSpec, Inc. into C-Level Executives, Principals, and Business Owners within the Architectural industry.

- Any incoming leads from the marketing team were given to senior sales team members, as the newest member of their sales team I created my own pipeline through prospecting methods within general industry research, LinkedIn, and Salesforce.
- Self-generated a book of business and surpassed desired sales quota by exceeding daily call expectations. e.g. 45-60 calls a day depending on the amount of Webinar demonstrations I had scheduled to run but always exceeding the 30 calls per day activity expectation.
- Conducted regular weekly webinar presentations to groups of potential clients through GoToMeeting.

Advanced Enterprises Inc. – Westbrook, ME. March 2014 – April 2015 (1 year 2 months) Independent Sales Associate

- Top Performing Salesman: achieved the RTS (road to success) award among other achievements such as winning an all-expense paid weekend trip with the other top performing sales and management members of the organization.
- Conducted 2-3 hour B2C in-home presentations. Demonstrated a diverse home maintenance system, built ROI, used conversational selling, handled objections and rebounded with feel felt found among other techniques to close the sale of the Kirby.

Experience Prior to March 2014 redacted but available at request.

Education and Certifications:

Currently enrolled:

- Udemy.com course Python Bootcamp Zero to Hero.
- The University of New Hampshire Full Stack Development Bootcamp

Completed:

- Highschool, Freeport, ME. Diploma
- VTEC Training in Portland, ME. Microsoft Outlook SME Training
- State of Maine Department of Professional & Financial Regulation, Bureau of Insurance Life & Health Insurance Certification (expired)

Volunteering:

Maine Boys to Men Leadership Program - R.S.V.P. (Reducing Sexism and Violence Program)

Other Activities and Interests:

- An active volunteer for the Maine Boys to Men organization.
- Built a top end Gaming PC successfully with no supervision as an independent project to learn more about A+ certifications.
- Currently self-teaching the commonly used programming and coding languages seen today such as SQL, Tableau, HTML, CSS, Python, C#, C+, and JavaScript.
- Woodworking and carpentry. Model building, aircraft models, other technical models.
- Mentor, and Student Program Board at Freeport High School.
- Aviation beginning at the age of 10: Successfully took off, flew and landed multiple single engine prop planes under the direct supervision of a Licensed Flight Instructor at various small airstrips in Maine.